<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<section id="GuideReferenceStandardPlugins">
  <title id="titleGuideReferenceStandardPlugins">Standard Plugins</title>
  <para>The following plugins are supplied as standard with Geeqie.</para>
  <section id="Applytheorientationtoimagecontent">
    <title>Apply the orientation to image content</title>
    <para>This command affects only jpeg, tiff and png files. The image file on disk is rotated to the orientation as specified by its Exif Orientation tag.</para>
    <warning>
      <para>External commands exiftran, exiv2 and mogrify, are used to implement this command.</para>
    </warning>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Edit/Orientation</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Cameraimport">
    <title>Camera import</title>
    <para>Imports images from an attached camera to the current folder. If a file with the same name already exists it will not be overwritten, and the new image will not be downloaded.</para>
    <para>File names on digital cameras are not necessarily unique. In some cases the same file name can exist in more than one sub-folder on the camera. As existing images will not be overwritten, subsequent files of the same name will not be downloaded. In this case a dialog will be shown to warn you of this.</para>
    <para>
      You may use the gphoto2 option
      <code>--filename</code>
      option to ensure that all filenames are unique when downloading. Refer to the
      <ulink url="http://www.gphoto.org/doc/manual/ref-gphoto2-cli.html">gphoto2 documentation.</ulink>
    </para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Exifdatetimetofile">
    <title>Exif datetime to file</title>
    <para>
      Sets the file datetime (mtime) to the Exif.Image.DateTimeOriginal value. If the exif tag does not exist, no action is taken.
      <para />
      This may be useful if you wish to sort on Exif.Image.DateTimeOriginal. This requires that the metadata for all files in the folder must be read each time. This is time consuming. If this operation is carried out when images are imported from the camera, future sorting can utilize file datetime which will be much faster.
    </para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Exportjpeg">
    <title>Export jpeg</title>
    <para>
      Extracts an embedded jpeg from a raw image to a file in the
      <code>/tmp</code>
      folder. If you wish to to keep this image, it must be copied or moved.
      <para />
      If
      <code>jpgicc</code>
      is installed, the image will be colour-corrected for the currently selected rendering intent.
    </para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Imagecrop">
    <title>Image crop</title>
    <para>
      If rectangle coordinates have been set by
      <emphasis role="strong">Edit/Draw Rectangle</emphasis>
      , a cropped image will be stored in the
      <code>/tmp</code>
      folder. If you wish to to keep this image, it must be copied or moved.
    </para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      and
      <emphasis role="strong">Edit</emphasis>
      menus.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="OpenWith">
    <title>Open With</title>
    <para>Call the standard GTK application chooser for a single file.</para>
    <para>
      This item is also displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">File</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Randomimage">
    <title>Random image</title>
    <para>Selects and displays a random image from a list of all images in Collections and the currently displayed folder.</para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="downsize">
    <title>Resize image</title>
    <para>Reduce the size of an image.</para>
    <table frame="all">
      <tgroup cols="2" rowsep="1" colsep="1">
      <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1*"/>
      <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>Option</entry>
            <entry>Meaning</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Required size kB</entry>
            <entry>desired output file size in kilobytes</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Tolerance %</entry>
            <entry>tolerance or allowed size of result greater than desired size expressed as percent of desired</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Max. iterations</entry>
            <entry>maximum number of iterations to stop</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Copy if unchanged</entry>
            <entry>
              copy to output when not downsizing and no image
              format change
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Strip metadata</entry>
            <entry>strip all meta data</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Show computation</entry>
            <entry>show the values of each iteration</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Open output file in Geeqie</entry>
            <entry>on successful conversion set Geeqie focus to the file</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <para>
      This plugin uses the Downsize script. The original may be found
      <ulink url="http://www.fmwconcepts.com/imagemagick/downsize/index.php">here.</ulink>
      It is subject to the following copyright:
    </para>
    <programlisting>
      Copyright © Fred Weinhaus

      My scripts are available free of charge for non-commercial (non-profit) use, ONLY.

      For use of my scripts in commercial (for-profit) environments or non-free applications,
      please contact me (Fred Weinhaus) for licensing arrangements. My email address is fmw at
      alink dot net.

      If you:
      1) redistribute,
      2) incorporate any of these scripts into other free applications or
      3) reprogram them in another scripting language, then you must contact me for permission,
      especially if the result might be used in a commercial or for-profit environment.

      Usage, whether stated or not in the script, is restricted to the above licensing
      arrangements. It is also subject, in a subordinate manner, to the ImageMagick license, which
      can be found at: http://www.imagemagick.org/script/license.php
    </programlisting>
    <para />
  </section>
  <section id="Symlink">
    <title>Symlink</title>
    <para>Creates a symbolic link on the selected files. If a file has sidecars, they will also be symlinked.</para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">File</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section id="Tetheredphotography">
    <title>Tethered photography</title>
    <para>
      If a camera is connected to the computer via USB, photos taken are immediately downloaded to the current folder and displayed on the computer.
      <para />
      If a file already exists with the same name, it is not overwritten but the download will not take place.
      <para />
      Auto-rename can be achieved with the --filename option of gphoto2.
      <para />
      In file
      <code>$HOME/.config/gphoto2/settings</code>
      , set the option:
      <code>gphoto2=filename=&lt;see the gphoto2 manual&gt;</code>
    </para>
    <para>
      This item is displayed in the
      <emphasis role="strong">Plugins</emphasis>
      menu.
    </para>
  </section>
</section>
